Guide to the Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals
Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals
- IBM Systems, 1972-1981; 10 linear feet
  - IBM Multiuse Communications Loop. Planning Guide, Dec 1979 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - IBM OS Full American National Standard COBOL, Nov 1976 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - IBM System/370 and 4300 Processors. Bibliography, Oct 1979 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - IBM System/370 and 4300 Processors. Bibliography, Jan 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - IBM System/370 and 4300 Processors. Bibliography, Nov 1980 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - IBM System/370. Bibliography of Industry Systems and Application Programs, Jul 1978 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - IBM System/370. Input/Output Configurator, May 1980 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - IBM System/370. Subsystem Support Services Logic. Levels 4 and 5, Feb 1977 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CMS Command and Macro Reference, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CMS User's Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CP Command Reference for General Users, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Environmental Recording Editing and Printing (EREP) Program, Oct 1976 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Environmental Recording Editing and Printing (EREP) Program Logic, Oct 1976 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Interactive Problem Control System (IPCS) User's Guide, Aug 1980 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Introduction, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Glossary and Master Index, Sep 1979 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: OLTSEP and Error Recording Guide, Aug 1977 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: OLTSEP and Error Recording Guide, Dec 1977-Apr 1978 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Operating Systems in a Virtual Machine, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Operator's Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Planning for Release 3, Oct 1975 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Planning for Release 4, Mar 1977 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - IBM Virtual machine Facility/370: Planning and System Generation Guide, Jan 1980 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Planning and System Generation Guide, Mar 1980 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Release 5 Guide, Feb 1978 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Release 6 Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Remote Spooling Communications Subsystem (RSCS) User's Guide, Dec 1976 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Remote Spooling Communications Subsystem (RSCS) User's Guide, Aug 1977 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: System Messages, Jun 1979 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: System Messages, Mar 1980 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: System Programmer's Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Terminal User's Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - IBM VS COBOL for DOS/VSE, May 1981 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Installing the Distributed Processign Control Executive/3790 Host Support for use with OS/VS, Mar 1980 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - An Introduction to the IBM 3101 Display Terminal, Aug 1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Introduction to the IBM 3704 and 3705 Communications Controllers, Sep 1978 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - An Introduction to the IBM 3790 Communication System, Apr 1979 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - An Introduction to the IBM 8100 Information System, Jun 1980 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - An Introduction to the IBM 8775 Display Terminal, Nov 1980 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to RPG II Report Writing, Jul 1978 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Introduction to VTAM (Virtual Telecommunications Access Method) Level 2, May 1977 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Network Control Program/TCAM. Network User's Guide, Jun 1974 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Network Job Interface. General Information Manual, Apr 1977 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Operator's Library: IBM System/370 Model 148 Operating Procedures, Dec 1976 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Operator's Library DOS/VS Operating Procedures, Mar 1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS Console Configurations, Sep 1976 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS TCAM, Jan 1977 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS1 CRJE, Jun 1972 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS1 Display Consoles, Mar 1975 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS1 Reference, Jan 1979 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Operator's Library: OS/VS2 TCAM, Sep 1974 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - OS/MFT, OS/MVT, and OS/VS1: CRJE Concepts and Facilities, Apr 1975 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - OS/MFT, OS/MVT, and OS/VS1: CRJE System Programmer's Guide, Oct 1975 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - OS/MFT, OS/MVT, and OS/VS1: CRJE Terminal User's Guide, Apr 1975 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - OS/MFT and OS/MVT TCAM Level 5 Component Release Guide, Dec 1976 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - OS/MFT and OS/MVT TCAM Logic (1 of 2), May 1973 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - OS/MFT and OS/MVT TCAM Logic (2 of 2), May 1973 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - OS/MFT and OS/MVT TCAM Programmer's Guide (1 of 2), May 1973 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - OS/MFT and OS/MVT TCAM Programmer's Guide (2 of 2), May 1973 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - OS/MVT and OS/VS2 TSO Terminals, Apr 1976 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - OS Power Warning Feature (PWF) Support, Mar 1974 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - OS TCAM. Concepts and Facilities, Jan 1973 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - OS TCAM. User's Guide, May 1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS Display Exception Monitoring Facility. System Information, Mar 1979 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS Display Exception Monitoring Facility. User's Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS Dynamic Support System, Nov 1973 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS Loader Logic, Jul 1972 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS Message Library: Utilities Messages, Nov 1975 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS Message Library: VS1 System Messages, Jul 1979 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS Message Library: VS1 System Messages, Jul 1980 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS Message Library: VS1 System Codes, Jan 1980 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - OS/VS System Modification Program (SMP). System Programmer's Guide, Jul 1977 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - OS/VS System Modification Program (SMP). System Programmer's Guide, Sep 1980 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS Tape Labels, Nov 1978 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS TCAM Application. Programmer's Guide, Feb 1978 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS TCAM Concepts and Applications, May 1976 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS TCAM Concepts and Facilities, Nov 1974 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS TCAM Debugging Guide, May 1977 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS TCAM Macro Reference Guide, Apr 1977 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS TCAM System Programmer's Guide (1 of 2), Jul 1978 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS TCAM System Programmer's Guide (2 of 2), Jul 1978 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - OS/VS TCAM User's Guide, Nov 1975 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS Utilities VS1 Release 5 and VS2 Release 3, Feb 1975 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS Utilities VS1 Release 6 and VS2 Release 3, Feb 1975 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS-VM/370 Assembler Logic, Mar 1974 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS-VM/370 Assembler Programmer's Guide, Oct 1975 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS1 3031, 3032, 3033 Processor Support Selectable Unit System Information, Mar 1978 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS1 Access Method Services, Jul 1978 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS1 Access Method Services Logic, Sep 1976 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS1 BDAM Logic, Dec 1973 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS1 Catalog Management Logic, Feb 1975 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS1 Checkpoint/Restart, Sep 1976 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS1 Checkpoint/Restart, Jul 1980 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS1 Data Management Services Guide, Sep 1976 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS1 Data Management Services Guide, Jul 1980 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS1 Data Management for System Programmers, Nov 1975 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS1 Debugging Guide, Jan 1980 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS1 ISAM Logic, Dec 1973 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - OS/VS1 JCL Reference, Jan 1979 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - OS/VS1 Job Management Logic Volume 2, Jan 1979 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - OS/VS1 Master Index, May 1975 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - OS/VS1 OLTEP, Mar 1975 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS1 OLTEP Logic, Apr 1976 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS1 Open/Close/EOV Logic, Sep 1976 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS1 Planning and Use Guide, Jul 1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS1 Release 4 VTAM Debugging Guide, Mar 1976 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS1 Release 6 Guide, Sep 1976 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS1 Release 7 Guide, Jul 1979 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS1 RES RTAM and Workstation Support Logic, Sep 1976 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS1 RES System Programmer's Guide, Sep 1976 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - OS/VS1 SAM Logic, Nov 1975 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - OS/VS1 Storage Estimates, Jan 1979 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS1 Subsystem Attachment Support Selection Unit System Information, Oct 1977 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS1 System Generation Reference, Jan 1980 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS1 System Management Facilities (SMF), Sep 1976 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS1 TCAM Logic (1 of 2), Feb 1975 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS1 TCAM Logic (2 of 2), Feb 1975 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS1 TCAM Programmer's Guide (1 of 2), Aug 1975 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS1 TCAM Programmer's Guide (2 of 2), Aug 1975 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - OS/VS1 Utilities, Dec 1977 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - OS/VS1 Virtual Storage Access Method (VSAM) Logic (1 of 2), Feb 1975 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS1 Virtual Storage Access Method (VSAM) Logic (2 of 2), Feb 1975 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS1 VTAM Data Areas, Nov 1975 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS1 VTAM Debugging Guide, Sep 1976 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS1 VTAM System Programmer's Guide, Nov 1975 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS1 to OS/VS2 MVS Conversion Notebook, Jan 1978 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS2 I/O Supervisor Logic, Dec 1978-Oct 1979 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Conversion Notebook, Apr 1978 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Conversion Notebook, Dec 1978 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Interactive Problem Control System User's Guide and Reference, Oct 1979 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS2 MVS JES2 Logic (1 of 2), May 1976 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS2 MVS JES2 Logic (2 of 2), May 1976 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Multiprocessing: An Introduction and Guide to Writing Operating and Recovery Procedures, Dec 1977 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Overview, Jun 1978 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - OS/VS2 MVS Performance Notebook, Dec 1977 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - OS/VS2 MVS System Programming Library: Job Management, Oct 1978 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - OS/VS2 MVS System Programming Library: TSO, Dec 1978 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - OS/VS2 System Logic Library, Aug 1977 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - OS/VS2 System Programming Library: Supervisor, Aug 1979 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - OS/VS2 System Programming Library: System Generation Reference and System Library Supplement, Jan 1979 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Synchronous Data Link Control. General Information, Mar 1979 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - System/370 Model 158. Operating Procedures, Apr 1979 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - System Installation Productivity Option (IPO) for OS/VS1. General Information and Planning Guide, May 1980 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - System Installation Productivity Option (IPO) for OS/VS2 Release 3.8 (MVS and MVS/System Extensions). Planning an MVS/MSE System IPO Installation, Apr 1979 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Systems Network Architecture. General Information, Jan 1975 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Teleprocessing Preinstallation Guide for IBM 3704 and 3705 Communications Controllers, May 1977 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - VM System IPO/Extended Release 2.0. Planning Guide, May 1980 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - VM/VSE System IPO/Extended Release 2.0. Planning Guide (1 of 2), Jul 1980 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - VM/VSE System IPO/Extended Release 2.0. Planning Guide (2 of 2), Jul 1980 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - VSE System Installation Productivity Option/Extended: Release 3.0. Planning Guide, Nov 1981 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - VSE System IPO/Extended VM System IPO/Extended VM/VSE System IPO/Extended Release 2.0. General Information Manual, Aug 1980 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- IBM System Library Supplement, 1978-1979; 0.08 linear feet
  The IBM System Library Supplement series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CMS Command and Macro Reference, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CMS User's Guide, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: CP Command Reference for General Users, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Operator's Guide, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: Planning and System Generation Guide, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: System Messages, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370: System Programmer's Guide, Apr 1978 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - OS/VS2 MVS/System Extensions, Sep 1979 (Box 49, Folder 14)
- IBM System Reference Library, 1963-1978; 1.5 linear feet
  The IBM System Reference Library series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - DOS Tape and Disk Sort/Merge Program, Jun 1973 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - FORTRAN II. General Information Manual, Dec 1963 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - IBM 1403 Printer Component Description, Jun 1974 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - IBM 2821 Control Unit Componenet Description, Feb 1972 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - IBM 7090/7094 IBSYS Operating System. Version 13. FORTRAN IV Language, Nov 1965 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - IBM OS Full American National Standard COBOL, Jun 1975 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - IBM OS Full American National Standard COBOL, Dec 1975 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - IBM Remote Multiplexers and Communications Terminals Installation Manual. Physical Planning, Feb 1978 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - IBM System/360 FORTRAN IV Language, Oct 1968 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - IBM System/360 FORTRAN IV Language. Handbook for Conversion from IBM 7090/7094 FORTRAN IV, Jun 1969 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - IBM System/360 FORTRAN IV Library Subprograms, Oct 1968 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Basic FORTRAN IV (E) Compiler Installation Reference Material, Jun 1970 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Basic FORTRAN IV (E) Programmer's Guide, Jul 1969 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Basic Telecommunications Access Method, Jun 1977 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Graphic Programming Services (GPS) for IBM 2260 Display Station (Local Attachment), Jan 1972 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Job Control Language Reference, Aug 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Messages and Codes (1 of 2), Mar 1976 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Messages and Codes (2 of 2), Mar 1976 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Operator's Guide for Display Consoles, May 1975 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Problem Determination Aids and Messages and Codes for GPS and GSP, Mar 1972 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. PL/I (F) Programmer's Guide (1 of 2), Sep 1972 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. PL/I (F) Programmer's Guide (2 of 2), Sep 1972 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. PL/I Subroutine Library Computational Subroutines, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Programmer's Guide to Debugging, Aug 1974 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. RDE Guide, Apr 1973 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Remote Job Entry, Jan 1972 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. System Control Blocks, Mar 1972 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. TESTRAN, Nov 1968 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Time Sharing Option. Command Language Reference, Mar 1972 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Time Sharing Option. Guide to Writing a Terminal Monitor Program or a Command Processor, Mar 1972 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - OS Assembler Language, Apr 1976 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - OS Sort/Merge Program, Feb 1973 (Box 52, Folder 10)
- IBM Technical Bulletin, 1973-1981; 0.13 linear feet
  The IBM Technical Bulletin series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. CICS/VS High Level Programming Interface, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. DB/DC Data Dictionary Release 2 Implementation Guide, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. IMS/MVS Performance Monitoring and Tuning Guide, Jan 1978 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. Maintaining Remote 4300 Processors in the Distributed Environment. An MVS Host - DOS/VSE Node Perspective, Apr 1979 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. SNA 3274/3276 Installation Guide, Mar 1979 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Palo Alto Systems Center. SNA Product Installation Guide, Feb 1979 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Poughkeepsie Systems Center. IBM System/370 Tracking and Resolving Problems and Coordinating Changes, Jun 1975 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Poughkeepsie Systems Center. Performance Newsletter VM/370 Benchmark Experience, Oct 1973 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Poughkeepsie Systems Center. VM/370 CMS Batch Experiences, Oct 1973 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Poughkeepsie Systems Center. VM/370 Performance Guide II, Jul 1974 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Washington Systems Center. An MVS Tuning Perspective, Jan 1981 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Washington Systems Center. VM/370 Performance Evaluation and Tuning Guidelines, Jan 1976 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Washington Systems Center. VM/VS 1 Performance Study 370/158 and 3031, Aug 1979 (Box 53, Folder 13)
- IBM World Trade Systems Center, 1976-1979
  The IBM World Trade Systems Center series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - 138/148 System Selection Guide OS/VS1, Sep 1976 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - DB/DC DATA DICTIONARY Release 3 Implementation Primer, Sep 1979 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - IMS Application Development Facility Application Developer's Guide, Sep 1979 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - MVS/System Extensions Tuning Cookbook, Aug 1979 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - VM/370 Tuning and Installation Cookbook, Apr 1976 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - VSAM Primer and Reference, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 4)
- Applied Data Research, 1969-1981; 1.08 linear feet
  The Applied Data Research series contains computer manuals that were produced by Applied Data Research: The On-Line Software Builders
  - COBOL/CP. Conversion Procedures User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - COBOL/DV. Miscellaneous Programs and Procedures. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - COBOL/DV. Program Development Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - COBOL/DV. Program Development User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - COBOL/DV. Report Writing Technique User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - COBOL/DV. Verification Facilities User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - COBOL/DV. Verification Facilities User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - COBOL/QDM. Utility Procedures User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - COBOL/QDM. Utility Procedures User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - COBOL/SP. CSP User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - COBOL/SP. Structured Programming User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - COBOL/SP. Structured Programming User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - MetaCOBOL. CSP User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - MetaCOBOL. OS Installation Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - MetaCOBOL. User Guide. Version 9, Jan 1979 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - MetaCOBOL. User Guide. Version 9.1, Aug 1979 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - The Librarian. OS File Access Interface Routines (FAIR), Apr 1981 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - The Librarian. Software Lock Facility, May 1979 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - The Librarian. Summary of Messages, Nov 1980 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - The Librarian. User Reference Manual, Nov 1980 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - The Librarian. User Routine Abstracts, Nov 1980 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - The Librarian/VS. Handbook, Nov 1979 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - COBOL/IMS. An Overview, Undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - COBOL/IMS. User Guide. Preliminary Test Documentation, Aug 1979
  - SL/1 (Systems Language/1), Undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - ADPAC. Programmer's Reference Manual (1 of 3), 1969 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - ADPAC. Programmer's Reference Manual (2 of 3), 1969 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - ADPAC. Programmer's Reference Manual (3 of 3), 1969 (Box 56, Folder 6)